<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://garden.jokens.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1900-Russian-Opposition-Group-Liberals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1900-Russian-Opposition-Group-Liberals/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Consisted of mostly middle classes.
Aims Free elections and a parliament Tsar to become a constitutional monarch like in England Civil rights Support Middle and educated classes: teachers, doctors, lawyers, and some industrialists Tactics Meetings, speeches, discussions, publishing books and articles calling for change</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1900-Russian-Opposition-Social-Democrats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1900-Russian-Opposition-Social-Democrats/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Founded in 1895.
Followed the teachings of Karl Marx, specifically they hope for a Communist Russia. Revolution should be started by workers in concentrated cities.
Aims To overthrow the Tsarist government To create a socialist state Support Workers in cities and towns Students Tactics Split into the Bolsheviks and Mensheviks due to different tactics</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1900-Russian-Opposition-Socialist-Revolutionaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1900-Russian-Opposition-Socialist-Revolutionaries/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Founded in 1901.
Aims To get rid of the Tsarist government To give the land to peasants in collective communes Support Mainly appealed to the peasants, also called the &amp;ldquo;Peasant&amp;rsquo;s Party&amp;rdquo; Tactics Propaganda Terrorism, especially on government officials</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1905-Changes-In-The-Russian-Countryside/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1905-Changes-In-The-Russian-Countryside/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Introduced by Pyotr-Stolypin Peasants were allowed to buy land from their neighbors A peasant&amp;rsquo;s bank was set up A new class of rich peasants - Kulaks - that is loyal to the government Effect Production of grain did increase Poorer peasants were forced to sell land and seek for other jobs Many were encouraged to settle by the Trans-Siberian Railway, but found no land/job Reforms interrupted by the war</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1905-Russian-Duma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1905-Russian-Duma/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Set up under the October Manifesto due to the demands of the Liberals Elections were biased: there was one representative for every 2,000 nobles, but only one for every 90,000 workers.
It first met in April 1906.
Operates under Stolypin Later became the Provisional Government Powers Could not pass laws Could not appoint ministers Could not control finance in many areas Under full control of the Tsar</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1919-Treatu-of-Neuilly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1919-Treatu-of-Neuilly/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The treaty signed in the Paris Peace Conference that dealt with the post-war treatment of Bulgaria.
Terms Land Lost land to Greece, Romania, and Yugoslavia.
In addition, it lost its access to the Mediterranean.
Army The army was limited to 20,000 men.
Reparations Bulgaria had to pay £100 millions in reparations.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1919-Treaty-of-St-Germain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1919-Treaty-of-St-Germain/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content This treaty dealt with the post-war treatment of Austria, signed in the WW1-Paris-Peace-Conference .
Terms Land The treaty separated Austria from Hungary and confirmed that Austria was no longer a leading power.
Bohemia-Moravia was divided into the new state of Czechoslovakia.
Bosnia-Herzegovina &amp;amp; Croatia were divided into the new state of Yugoslavia.
Galacia was given to Poland. Other land were divided by Italy.
Forbidden to unite with Germany.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1920-The-Treaty-of-Sevres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1920-The-Treaty-of-Sevres/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The treaty signed in the Paris Peace Conference that dealt with the post-war treatment of Turkey.
Terms Land A substantial amount of territory was lost, and its empire was broken up. Parts of Turkey were defined as zones of influence controlled by Italy, Britain, or France.
Armenia and Kurdistan became independent.
Economy Turkey&amp;rsquo;s tax system, finances, and budget were to be controlled by the Allies.
Army The army was limited to 50,000 men.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1920-The-Treaty-of-Trianon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1920-The-Treaty-of-Trianon/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The treaty signed in the Paris Peace Conference that dealt with the post-war treatment of Hungary. It was not signed until 1920.
Terms Land Many territories and populations were lost to neighbors.
Reparations It was due to pay reparations, but its economy was so weak that it never did.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1923-Corfu-Crisis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1923-Corfu-Crisis/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content An Italian general called Tellini was appointed to supervise the border between Greece and Albania. On 27th of August, Tellini and his team was killed on the Greek side. On 31th of August, Benito-Mussolini bombarded and then occupied Corfu. 15 were killed.
The League reacted by condemning Mussolini to retreat, asking Greece to pay compensations if Tellini&amp;rsquo;s killers were to be found.
Mussolini refused. Britain wanted to refused, but the French backed the Italians as French forces were tied in the Ruhr conflict .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1923-Ruhr-Conflict/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1923-Ruhr-Conflict/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content According to the Treaty of Versailes , Germany had to pay lots of reparations. They were paid in 1921, but not in 1922, which, in 1923, caused French and Belgium Soldiers to invade the Ruhr region to loot what was owed to them in the form of raw materials and goods.
Workers in the Ruhr were ordered by the German government to go on a strike. The French reacted by killing over 100 and expelling 100,000 from the region.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/1938-Anschluss-with-Austria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/1938-Anschluss-with-Austria/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content There was a strong Nazi party in Austria. Hitler encouraged them to stir up trouble.
Austrian Chancellor Schushnigg asked Britain and France for help with no response, so he held a plebiscite.
Hitler was afraid of losing, so he marched his troops into Austria, resulting in a 99.75%.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Alexander-Kerensky/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Alexander-Kerensky/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Member of the Social Revolutionaries . Elected to the Duma in 1912, and had high support in the public.
Often met the crowds to discuss their needs. Later he became the Minister of Justice within the Provisional Government Provisional Government. He also went to meetings of the Petrograd Soviet , and made sure they understood each other.
Later became the first Minister of War, and eventually, Prime Minister.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/American-Involvment-in-the-League-of-Nations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/American-Involvment-in-the-League-of-Nations/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content After the League was set up, Wilson started campaigning in the US to join the League. However, Wilson&amp;rsquo;s opponents utilized criticism against the League, won, and refused to join the League.
Hatred Many Americans were of German heritage, and hated the Treaty-Of-Versailles Army People did not want American soldiers fighting on the other side of the war for other causes.
Sanctions American businesses did not want to suffer from trade sanctions imposed by the League.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Assassination-Of-Rasputin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Assassination-Of-Rasputin/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Prince Felix Yusupov did not have a good reason to murder [Rasputin was damaging the royal family&amp;rsquo;s reputation](Gregory-Rasputin]]. He claimed it was for the good of Russia after fleeing from Russia. [[Relationship-Between-Rasputin-And-The-Royal-Family). Some historians suggested British involvement to prevent Russia from withdrawing from the war, but it was certainly not the British who committed the act.
The act was well plotted. He invited Rasputin to the Moika Palace for a party.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Basic-Economic-Problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Basic-Economic-Problem/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content How to best allocate resources in order to satisfy people&amp;rsquo;s unlimited needs and wants with limited resources
Questions include
What to produce? How to produce? For whom to produce?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Bloody-Sunday-January-1905-The-Spark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Bloody-Sunday-January-1905-The-Spark/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Events The workers were in really bad conditions due to Economic Problems .
Priest Father Gapon organized a march in St. Petersburg on Sunday, January 22, to deliver a petition to the Tsar. Nearly 200,000 people came. The march was peaceful.
Cossacks marched into the crowd as troops opened fire. The casualties were estimated to be between hundreds to thousands.
Aftermath News quickly spread to other cities. Within a week, Russia was in full revolution.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Bosheviks-Seize-Power-November/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Bosheviks-Seize-Power-November/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content With the urge of Lenin , the Bolsheviks started their attack on Petrograd on November 7th, 1917. The Red Guards were well equipped, thanks to the Kornilov Affair .
Under command of Leon-Trotsky , they quickly took control of the bridges, railways, and so on. Alexander-Kerensky fled with a car lent by the American Embassy. The next day they seized key places such as the state bank. They stormed the Winter Palace with little resistance.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Causes-of-Failure-of-International-Peace-by-1939/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Causes-of-Failure-of-International-Peace-by-1939/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Militarism japan, Italy, and Germany began to rapidly expand their army.
Great Depression Britain, France, and other countries that relied on America&amp;rsquo;s economy suffered heavily, and lost budget to rearm, making them less likely to involve in international affairs, leading to appeasement
The-Great-Depression Hitler&amp;rsquo;s Rise to Power Hitler came to power in 1933, and has an aggressive foreign policy</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Consequences-of-the-Treaty-of-Versailles-on-Germany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Consequences-of-the-Treaty-of-Versailles-on-Germany/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Political Violence Right-wing opponents attempted a revolution to Ebert&amp;rsquo;s government, known as the Kapp Putsch. It was defeated by a strike, but added chaos and bitterness towards the Treaty.
It also gave Hitler a common enemy to direct hatred towards, leading to his rise to power, where he vowed to [abolish the Treaty of Versailles](Hitler-foreign-policy-aims#Abolish Treaty of Versailles)
Ruhr Conflict See: 1923-Ruhr-Conflict Hyperinflation As mentioned in the [#Ruhr Conflict](#Ruhr Conflict), to pay of the reparations the German government began printing loads of money, leading to hyperinflation.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Demand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Demand/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The willingness and ability of customers to pay a given price to buy a good or service.
Determinants Habits, fashions, and tastes Income Substitutes and complements Advertisement Government policies Economy</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Distributability-of-Responsibility-and-Necessity-of-Law/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Distributability-of-Responsibility-and-Necessity-of-Law/</guid><description>Tags #thoughts, #philosophy, #jurisprudence
Content Responsibility can be distributed. For every single event, every single entity&amp;rsquo;s existence and action that takes place before it takes credit. Of course, this sphere of effect expands reversely in time at the speed of light. One can affect events one light year away a year later, but not at the moment.
Therefore, it is impractical to determine the punishment of events based on responsibility. One might consider the possibility of an entity of preventing or modifying an event, weighing it with the possibility of other entities.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Dual-Power-After-March-1917-Revolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Dual-Power-After-March-1917-Revolution/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content After the [Petrograd Soviet](Russian-1917-March-Revolution]], both the [[Petrograd-Soviet) and the Provisional Government went to power. The Provisional Government could only carry out decisions if the Soviets agreed.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Economic-Agents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Economic-Agents/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The decision makers of an economy
Main economic agents include
individuals or households firms the government The economic agents decide on the Basic-Economic-Problem</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Economic-Goods-and-Free-Goods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Economic-Goods-and-Free-Goods/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content Economic Good One which is limited in supply, and requires effort to obtain
Free Good Unlimited in supply, and has no Opportunity-Cost in obtaining</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Economic-Problems-Of-Russia-In-1905/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Economic-Problems-Of-Russia-In-1905/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The Russian Government spent enormous amount of money on Russification. Some were borrowed, but most were from taxes.
In 1902 there was a slump, and unemployment rates skyrocketed. Poor harvests also occurred in 1900 and 1902. This caused widespread protests, riots, and demonstration. The Tsarist regime reacted with violence.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Factors-of-Production/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Factors-of-Production/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The four factors of production include
Land - the natural resources required in production, such as oil, coal, water, etc. rent as reward Labor - the human resources need in production wage &amp;amp; salary as reward Capital - the manufactured resources needed in production, e.g. machinery, tools, vehicles, etc. interest as reward Enterprise - the businessperson profit as reward Reward commonly known as income</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Flowchart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Flowchart/</guid><description>Tags #tags, #meta
Content Oval - Terminal - staring or ending
Flow lines - direction of flow
Parallelogram - IO / used for input output operation. Indicates that the computer is to obtain or output data
Rhombus - Decision - if/else blah
Rectangle - Process - internal operation inside the Processor or Memory
1 2 flowchart a([Start]) --&amp;gt; b[/READ r/] --&amp;gt; c[area = 3.1415926 * r * r] --&amp;gt; d[/output area/] --&amp;gt; f([end]) 1 2 3 4 flowchart a([START]) --&amp;gt; b[/READ a, b/] --&amp;gt; c{a &amp;gt; b} c -- TRUE --&amp;gt; d[/PRINT a/] --&amp;gt; f([END]) c -- FALSE --&amp;gt; e[/PRINT b/] --&amp;gt; f 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 flowchart a([START]) --&amp;gt; b[/READ math_grade, as_grade/] --&amp;gt; c{math_grade in &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;a&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;a*&amp;#39;} c -- True --&amp;gt; d{as_grade in &amp;#39;a&amp;#39;} c -- False --&amp;gt; app[/READ approval/] d -- False --&amp;gt; app --&amp;gt; check{approval == &amp;#39;yes&amp;#39;} -- True --&amp;gt; yes check -- False --&amp;gt; no[/PRINT &amp;#39;No&amp;#39;/] --&amp;gt; gend d -- True --&amp;gt; yes[/PRINT &amp;#39;Yes&amp;#39;/] --&amp;gt; gend([END]) app --&amp;gt; gend 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 flowchart s([START]) --&amp;gt; i[/READ year/] --&amp;gt; l{year MOD 400 == 0} l -- False --&amp;gt; ll{year MOD 100 == 0} ll -- True --&amp;gt; lll{year MOD 4 == 0} lll -- False --&amp;gt; no[/PRINT no/] l -- True --&amp;gt; yes[/PRINT yes/] ll -- False --&amp;gt; yes lll -- True --&amp;gt; yes --&amp;gt; e([END]) no --&amp;gt; e</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Geographical-Mobility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Geographical-Mobility/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The willingness and ability of a person to relocate from one area to another for employment. Factors-of-Production Factors include
Family ties and related commitments Cost of living</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/German-Criticism-of-the-Treaty-Of-Versailles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/German-Criticism-of-the-Treaty-Of-Versailles/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The Treaty-Of-Versailles was hated by the German population.
War Guilt Germans felt that the blame was unfair since they did not start the war. At least the blame should be shared.
Reparations Germany also lost millions of people during the war. Despite the lack of the working force, the Allies still demanded heavy reparations. Its main industrial areas were also stripped German-Criticism-of-the-Treaty-Of-Versailles#Land Also see: 1923-Ruhr-Conflict Disarmament Germany felt unfair that they were forced to disarm to 100,000, not even enough to defend, when the Allies made to promise to disarm.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Gregory-Rasputin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Gregory-Rasputin/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Summary Publicly known as a sex-maniac that has numerous relationships with prostitutes, noble ladies, and perhaps the Tsarina even.
Early Life Rasputin was born in a small village named Pokrovskoye where his ancestors settled sometime around mid-17th century. The family, as with other peasants living in Siberia, differed from the peasants working in Serfdom and, as noted, often abandoned their local officials during the night if they became too harsh.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Hitler-foreign-policy-aims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Hitler-foreign-policy-aims/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Four main aims
Lebensraum He wanted to gain land from Eastern Europe.
Defeat Communism Hitler wanted to carve an empire out of Russia&amp;rsquo;s Communism by defeating it.
Abolish Treaty of Versailles Hitler calls the government that signed the ToV the november criminals, utilizing German hatred He also argues that people should have self-determination
Anschluss with Austria 1938-Anschluss-with-Austria Sudetenland Saarland Hitler feared that the plebiscite promised by the ToV might not go well, but his propaganda was a success</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/League-Of-Nations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/League-Of-Nations/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Created under the proposal of Woodrow-Wilson in the Treaty-Of-Versailles .
Aims To discourage aggression To encourage co-operation, especially in business and trade To encourage disarmament To improve living standards of all mankind Collective Security As stated in article 10 of the treaty:
The members of the League undertake to preserve against external aggression the territory and existing independence of all members of the League. In case of threat of danger the Council [of the League] shall advise upon the means by which this obligation shall be fulfilled</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Lenins-April-Thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Lenins-April-Thesis/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Declarations/Demands that Lenin made after he returned to Russia in 1917.
Later transformed into the slogans &amp;ldquo;Bread, Peace, Land&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;All Power to the Soviets&amp;rdquo;
Demands There should be no co-operation between the Provisional Government and Soviets The War should be ended immediately Land should be given to the peasants Soviets should take full power Argues that there should be a second, Socialist revolution.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Machine-Translation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Machine-Translation/</guid><description>Tags #nlp, #neural-network, #statistics
Content Statistical Machine Translation 1990-2010
$$ \underset{y}{\mathrm{argmax}}P(y|x) $$
Bayes transformation. $P(x)$ is not needed in argmax, therefore dropped.
$$ = \underset{y}{\mathrm{argmax}}P(x|y)P(y) $$
Needs large amount of parallel data.
To learn model from corpus using alignment.
$$ P(x, a|y) $$
with $a$ as alignment (world level correspondence between source and target).
Some words have no corresponding target counterparts.
They can also be many 2 one, one 2 many, or many 2 many</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Macroeconomics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Macroeconomics/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The study of economic behavior and decision making in the whole economy
Studies include
The role of government Redistribution of income Fiscal policy Monetary policy Supply-side policy Economic growth Employment and unemployment Inflation and deflation</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Market-System/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Market-System/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The method of allocating scarce resources through the market forces of demand and supply
Market Equilibrium The point where the demand for a product matches supply</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Microeconomics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Microeconomics/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The study of particular markets and sections of an economy
Topics include
Factors-of-Production Demand Supply Price elasticity of demand Market failure Economies and diseconomies of scale Firms' costs, revenues and objectives Market Structure</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/NLP-index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/NLP-index/</guid><description>Tags #nlp, #neural-network, #statistics
Content Basics characters
words - formed by morphemes
syntax - the structure of sentence / word order
POS - part of speech tags
PTB - Penn tree-bank
sequence label
defining POS tags Symbolic rules cannot cover all cases By statistical model (e.g. HMM) a probabilistic model neural networks dynamic
Semantics Lexical semantics - relations between the word meanings</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/NN-Attention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/NN-Attention/</guid><description>Tags #neural-network
Content Compares current hidden state (dot product) with all previous hidden states. Gets a softmax score of similarity and uses the states combined in place of/in conjunction with the current hidden state to produce an output. Used in context of RNN/LSTM/GRU or derivatives.
improves NMT performance solves bottleneck problem helps with vanishing gradient provides some interpretability Types Basic dot-product attention
$$ e_i = s^Th_i \in \mathbb{R} $$</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Occupational-Mobility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Occupational-Mobility/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The ability of a person to change between jobs
See Also Factors-of-Production Geographical-Mobility</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/October-Manifesto-1905/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/October-Manifesto-1905/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Signed by the Tsar under the pressure of Sergei Witte .
It promised
Parliament (or Duma) elected by the people Civil rights (freedom of speech, conscience) Uncensored newspaper Right to form political parties Effect This satisfied the Liberals of their demands, reducing opposition in the 1905 Revolution</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Opportunity-Cost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Opportunity-Cost/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The next best opportunity (choice) forgone when making a decision</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Organizing-Stuff-With-Tags-And-Categories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Organizing-Stuff-With-Tags-And-Categories/</guid><description>Tags #productivity, #thoughts
Content As a general rule: do not use categories.
Most apps/websites/name anything provides two main ways of splitting items into groups: tags and categories. Both can be subdivided, but categories are mutually exclusive.
There is nothing wrong being mutually exclusive, but many times reality does not let us do so. Say, you may divide your diary entries into School and Family. What if one day, somehow, your teacher visits you home?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Orthodox-Religion-In-Russia-1900s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Orthodox-Religion-In-Russia-1900s/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Works in close relationship with the Russian Government Holy men in the religion were called Startsy (singular form Starets).
Divine Right of Kings The Orthodox Church taught that the Tsar was God&amp;rsquo;s representative on earth. This was known as the Divine Right of Kings</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Paris-Conference-Clemenceau-Aims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Paris-Conference-Clemenceau-Aims/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Clemenceau and other french leaders saw the treaty as a change to cripple Germany to prevent it from attacking again. He also wanted huge amount of reparations since France was damaged heavily during 202103141651-World-War-1 .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Paris-Conference-Wilson-Aims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Paris-Conference-Wilson-Aims/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Ideas presented by Woodrow-Wilson at the WW1-Paris-Peace-Conference Wilson did not want to be too harsh on Germany.
He also wanted to push for democracy in the defeated countries.
Self-determination should be given to minority groups.
More international co-operation.
Summarized into the Wilson-Fourteen-Points</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Paris-Congerence-Lloyd-George-Aims/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Paris-Congerence-Lloyd-George-Aims/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Lloyd George was worried that a harsh treaty would cause a Communist revolution in Germany. He also wanted to trade with Germany. Germany was Britain&amp;rsquo;s second large trading partner.
He also wanted Germany to lose its army, so that Britain can protect it&amp;rsquo;s empire.
He was pressured by the Britain people to impose a harsh treaty (such as reparations) since British was also damaged severely in 202103141651-World-War-1 .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Petrograd-Soviet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Petrograd-Soviet/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content A large group of representatives sent by workers and soldiers within the Winter Palace. Formed after the Russian-1917-March-Revolution .</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Power-Law-Distribution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Power-Law-Distribution/</guid><description>Tags #math, #statistics
Content Regular patterns of one level might not just mean that these events of constant level will happen constantly, but also signifies the possibility that events of higher magnitude may occur, or at least possess the possibility of so.
Can often be seen in earthquake statistical analysis.
Characteristics could include some 20/80 percent rules, where most consequences were caused by a small fraction of actual incidents.
When plotted on double-logarithmic scales, emerges as a linear graph.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Pretraining-NN/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Pretraining-NN/</guid><description>Tags #neural-network
#to-do
Content In a transformer:
decoder encoder encoder-decoder Pretraining decoder</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Production-Possibility-Curve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Production-Possibility-Curve/</guid><description>Tags #economics
Content The maximum combination of two (goods or services) which can be produced in an economy.
Movements along the PPC causes an opportunity cost Causes of Shifts of the Curve Increase in the quality or quantity of factors of production</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Pyotr-Stolypin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Pyotr-Stolypin/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Full name Pyotr Arkadyevich Stolypin.
Prime Minister of Russia from 1906 to 1911
He once prosecuted Rasputin out of St. Petersburg, but after Stolypin&amp;rsquo;s death Rasputin returned
Assassinated in September 1911
Reforms Introduced in 1905 1905-Changes-In-The-Russian-Countryside 1905-Russian-Duma</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Relationship-Between-Knowledge-Prediction-And-Functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Relationship-Between-Knowledge-Prediction-And-Functions/</guid><description>Tags #writing, #thoughts, #time, #free-will
Content There are many ways to structure a thought experiment where multiple consciousness gain access to time, where time is an abstract ability of knowledge and control over the linear dimension of time. For the sake of simplicity, let&amp;rsquo;s assume that multiple observers have the access to overseeing the to-come future, including its full state. They could adhere to the actions they saw they did in the future, preserving it, or they could do something else, thereby modifying it.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Relationship-Between-Rasputin-And-The-Royal-Family/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Relationship-Between-Rasputin-And-The-Royal-Family/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Introduction The only son in the Royal Family , Alexis, inherited hemophilia from her mother. This made him extremely ill. In search of treatment, Rasputin was introduced to the Tsarina as an extremely healing man.
By 1900, Rasputin was already within the circle of the upper society in St. Petersburg, many of whom described him as a humorous peasant with a fascinating charisma. However, he never had the chance to work his way into royalty.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Remilitarisation-of-the-Rhineland-1936/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Remilitarisation-of-the-Rhineland-1936/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The Rhineland was demilitarized according to [foreign policy](Treaty-Of-Versailles]], but Hitler wanted to re-militarize it in his [[Hitler-foreign-policy-aims).
In March 1936, he moved his troops into the Rhineland. If the French response, he would be forced to retreat and become a huge humiliation for him. To his fortune, they did not.
The attention of the League was upon the 202104131420-Abyssinian-Crisis , British people felt sympathy, and the French were having an election and no one wanted to be blamed for an war, creating Hitler&amp;rsquo;s success.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-Difficulties-To-Govern-In-1900/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-Difficulties-To-Govern-In-1900/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Size Russia was large. Takes about 1/6 of all land on earth.
4000 miles wide 2000 miles high Russia was large, but little could be used for farming. Only the Black Earth region was fertile.
Transportation Its transportation was less developed, with little roads. Long journeys were traveled by rivers or railways.
However, railway was not enough. Trans-Siberian railway opened by 1904, and took more than a week from Moscow to Vladivostok.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-July-Days/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-July-Days/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content After the March Revolution, people began to oppose the war. In July, Kerensy launched a major attack, which failed, sparking demonstrations, known as the July Days.
This improved the support of the Bosheviks , but they were not ready to seize power.
Kerensky ordered troops to force the demonstrations down, and prosecuted Bolshevik leaders as the culprit behind the riot. Lenin fled to Finland.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-Kornilov-Affair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-Kornilov-Affair/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Kerensky appoints a general called Kornilov as the head of the army. Kornilov wanted to remove the revolutionaries completely and establish his own government, so he marched his troops into Petrograd.
Kerensky, in panic, gave weapons to the Red Army of the Bolsheviks. Kornilov never reached Petrograd due to resistance along the way, but the Red Army kept their rifles.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-Sovnakom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russia-Sovnakom/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Sovnakom stands for the Council of People&amp;rsquo;s Commissars.
Of which, Lenin was Chairman, Stalin was Commissar for Nationalities, and Trotsky was Commissar for War.
Decrees The Sovnamkom issued several decrees within the first months of its creation.
November A maximum 8-hour day &amp;amp; 48-hour week for industry Employment insurance No more titles (everyone were comrades) Women declared equal All non-Bolshevik paper banned December Liberal party, the Cadets, banned All factories under control of workers' committees All banks taken by government Army more democratic Church land taken by government Divorce became easier and marriages non-inclusive to churches</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-1900s-Tsarist-Family/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-1900s-Tsarist-Family/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Father: Tsar-Nicholas-II Mother: Tsarina-Alexandra Son: Alexis
Daughters (in order of birth date):
Olga Tatiana Maria Anastasia</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-1917-March-Revolution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-1917-March-Revolution/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Causes Russian-Participation-In-World-War-One Relationship-Between-Rasputin-And-The-Royal-Family Events March:
7th: 40,000 workers from Pulitov Engineering Works went on a strike 8th: International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day; demonstrations all over Petrograd. Continued for two days. Ordered by the Tsar to be put down by force, and did not take any notice 12th: many soldiers took sides with the crowd, some shot their officers 15th: Tsar abdicates on train Outcomes The Tsarist Government was removed from office The Duma became the Provisional Government The Petrograd Soviet was also set up</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Bolshevik-Party/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Bolshevik-Party/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content small party, disciplined, professional revolutionaries to seize power when the time was right small groups would coordinate and organize strikes in factories Took control of Russia after November Revolution . Later known as the communists.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Government-In-1900s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Government-In-1900s/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Nicholas the Second was the Tsar ruling Russia. The Tsarist system was autocratic: he had absolute control.
He had a council of ministers to run departments, but he still had the final control.
There was no political freedom. Censorship was common, and opposition were captured as political prisoners, jailed or exiled into Siberia by the secret police Okhrana
The soldiers and Cossacks helped restore order violently during protests, strikes, and riots.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Menshevik-Party/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Menshevik-Party/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Ideology To transform Russia into a socialist state
the party should be a mass organization that all workers should be allowed to join eventually grow to power</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Participation-In-World-War-One/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Participation-In-World-War-One/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Reasons for Entering the War The Tsar hoped that a common enemy would unite the Russian people War Many died without proper equipment, some even lacked basic clothing and boots. Russia loss heavily.
Effects Tsarist support became all-time high The Duma worked closely with the Tsar St. Petersburg was renamed to Petrograd Food shortage Factories closed Prices rose The Tsar was blamed for the loss of the war Royal family was criticized, especially because of the Relationship Between the Tsarina and Rasputin See Also 202103141651-World-War-1</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Provisional-Government/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Provisional-Government/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Set up as a temporary government after the 1917 Revolution . Formerly known as the Duma Mostly lead by Alexander-Kerensky .
Decisions Continued Russia Participation in World War One Did not give land to the peasants, wanted to wait. Peasants seized land themselves</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Revolution-Of-1905/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Revolution-Of-1905/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Causes Long Term Economic-Problems-Of-Russia-In-1905 Lower class repression Minority groups were discontent about Russification Short Term The Russo-Japan War Opposition groups Liberals Social Democrats Socialist Revolutionaries Direct The Spark (Bloody Sunday) Events January:
More than 400,000 workers on strike February:
Strikes spread, demanding 8-hour work day, higher wages, and better conditions 4th, Tsar&amp;rsquo;s uncle, Grand Duke Sergei, assassinated in Moscow March:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Society-Classes-1900/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russian-Society-Classes-1900/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Russia had clear structure of class.
Class Percentage Peasants 84% Military 5% Urban Workers 4% Government Officials 4% Nobility 1.5% Priests 1% Merchants 0.5% Peasants Most of the population were peasants. They had hard lives, ate bread and cabbage for life. Fish was common, but not meat.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russification/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Since Russia was difficult to govern due to its diversity of nationalities, there was a policy of Russification, in which non-Russians were forced to speak Russian, wear Russian clothes and follow Russian customs. Russian officials were responsible for non-Russian areas.
See Also Russia-Difficulties-To-Govern-In-1900</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Russo-Japan-War-Of-1904/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Russo-Japan-War-Of-1904/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The war began due to a fight for control of Manchuria. Russia wanted an evergreen port on their east cost.
Tsar thought that the war was a good idea. Victory would gain support of the people.
However, it caused inflation, shortages of food and goods, and lack of industrial materials.
The Russians were also heavily defeated by the Japanese.
Port Author fell to the Japanese in 1905.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Self-Attention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Self-Attention/</guid><description>Tags #neural-network, #nlp
Content Different to attention , in self attention, each word gets a corresponding $q_i$, $k_i$, $v_i$ as queries, keys, and values. They are calculated by multiplying the embedding input by $W^Q$, $W^K$, and $W^V$.
At each word, one round is run for each word, where $\mathrm{score}_1 = q_1 \cdot k_1$ and $\mathrm{score}_2 = q_1 \cdot k_2$, and divide all by $\sqrt{d_k}$. Softmax, and use the final as weights.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Sergei-Witte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Sergei-Witte/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content First Prime Minister of Russia, succeeded by Ivan Goremykin, who was later quickly replaced by Pyotr-Stolypin How significant was Sergei Witte for Russia up to 1914? Paper four question
As the first Prime Minister of Russia, Sergei Witte played an important role in Russia as both a source of reforms and a supporter of the Tsarist regime. To assess the significance of Sergei Witte, a comparison between him and one of his successors, Stolypin , could be used.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Stalin-economic-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Stalin-economic-policies/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Industry Five Year Plans Stalin had three five year plans before World-War-Two Agriculture USSR-collectivization</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Treaty-Of-Versailles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Treaty-Of-Versailles/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Treaty between the Allies and Germany that ended World War 1 .
Statements War Guilt Clause Also known as Article 231, this places Germany to be blamed completely for the cause of the war. Simple but seemed harsh to the Germans
Reparations Germany was to pay reparations to the Allies. Amount decided in 1921 to be £6,600 million. Modified later under the Young Plan
Land Effect on Germany:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Tsar-Nicholas-II/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Tsar-Nicholas-II/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Nikolai II Alexandrovich Romanov
He was kind, and devoted many to his family. However, sources say that he has spent too much time with his family and did not care enough on government issues.
Husband of Alexandra .
He was deeply religious, believed that he had the [Divine Right of Kings](Orthodox-Religion-In-Russia-1900s#Divine Right of Kings)
He also believed wholeheartedly in autocracy.
Despite that he wanted to bring happiness to his people, he knew little about the true lives of the lower classes, and his ministers would often tell him lies</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Tsarina-Alexandra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Tsarina-Alexandra/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Wife of Tsar Nicholas the Second .
Alexandra was German, and was a carrier of the disease hemophilia, which reduces the body&amp;rsquo;s ability to clot a cut. The disease was inherited by Alexis, her son.
She also believed that Nicholas II was chosen by God.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Ultimate-Motive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Ultimate-Motive/</guid><description>Tags #thoughts
#to-do
Content (20210808)
Is there an ultimate motive that can explain all human thoughts &amp;amp; activities?
(20210912)
It should be measurable, and ideally different for each individual at different point of times.
However, this would require a difference be defined for a human being and a non-living object (e.g. rock). Otherwise the question of whether abiding the rules of natural science is decisive and motive-caused would arise. Due to this link, there could as well be a clearer definition of free-will and perhaps a proof of the existence of souls.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/USSR-collectivization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/USSR-collectivization/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Peasants that worked alone were joined in to large farms that provided common necessities.
Productivity Peasants worked in strip farms, which made modern machinery inefficient. By introducing collectivization, productivity of agriculture would increase, as efficiency would increase, and collected farms would be able to afford these machinery
Coordination By introducing collectivization, grain collection of the government was made easier and more efficient.
It was also easier for government to inform peasants of what to produce.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Vladimir-Lenin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Vladimir-Lenin/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Leader of the Bolshevik Party Often known as the Driving Force of the Revolution
Modified the Communism theory to fit for Russia, later known as Leninism</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/We-Are-Social-People/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/We-Are-Social-People/</guid><description>Tags #writing, #thoughts
Content First of all, us humans are undeniably social creatures. We cannot live without help from others, and to do so, helping others. A simple proof will be to count the hours of each person being alone, and the hours of him/her communicating with other humans. Despite the attempts of becoming alone, I find myself in a desperate need of relationships. You see, people often has this falsified image that introverts tend to have a higher productivity than extroverts.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Wilson-Fourteen-Points/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Wilson-Fourteen-Points/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content Points that Wilson proposed to be written in the Treaty of Versailles .
Its content is as follows:
Diplomacy should be public with no secret treaties The sea should be free Nations should have free trade Colonies should be treated fairly Lost land should be returned to Russia Belgium should regain independence Alsace-Lorraine should be returned to France Italy&amp;rsquo;s borders to be redrawn People living in Austria-Hungary should be granted self-determination The Balkan states should also be guaranteed self-determination and independence Turks and those under Turkish rule should be granted self-determination An independent Poland should be created A general association of nations must be formed to mediate international disputes League-Of-Nations</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/WW1-Big-Three/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/WW1-Big-Three/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content The most important countries/men in the WW1-Paris-Peace-Conference .
Woodrow-Wilson , America Clemenceau, France Lloyd George, England</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/WW1-Paris-Peace-Conference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/WW1-Paris-Peace-Conference/</guid><description>Tags #history
Content A conference between the winning powers of 202103141651-World-War-1 . Took place between 1919 to 1920, lasting for 12 months. 32 countries was invited, but not even one of the defeated countries were.
Dominated by the Big Three .
Conflict Paris-Conference-Wilson-Aims Paris-Congerence-Lloyd-George-Aims Paris-Conference-Clemenceau-Aims Products Treaty-Of-Versailles League-Of-Nations</description></item><item><title/><link>https://garden.jokens.me/Zettelkasten-Wiki-Rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.jokens.me/Zettelkasten-Wiki-Rule/</guid><description>Tags #meta
Content TL;DR Long term learning should be the #1 focus for me (in many ways). Hence, this new vault&amp;rsquo;s gonna be started (hope it can persist) by the #zettelkasten #note-taking method.
This site shows the fundamentals.
Guidelines Generally, conform to the official guidelines Notes should be formatted with scalability and atomicity in mind. Don&amp;rsquo;t use categories but tags instead, more on that later More wiki-links There should be no short-term emotion related diary-like entries.</description></item></channel></rss>